newsmaker.com.au 2018-06-26

# Privacy Policy

At NewsMaker.com.au ("NewsMaker") we are committed to protecting the privacy and security of any personally identifiable information that you provide us. Personally identifiable information includes information that can be linked to a specific individual, such as name, address, phone number, or email address.

This privacy policy explains how NewsMaker, NewsGallery Pty Ltd and their associated businesses handle and protect your personally identifiable information in accordance with commonly accepted privacy principles. This policy was established on 1 May 2005. 

NewsMaker and its associated businesses reserve the right to modify or amend this policy at any time and for any reason. Any material changes to this privacy policy will be posted prior to their implementation. Questions regarding this policy should be emailed to Leila Henderson or sent via postal mail to: NewsGallery Pty. Ltd., Attention: Leila Henderson, CEO, NewsGallery Pty Ltd, PO Box 73, Highgate, South Australia 5063

## The Information We Collect

In an effort to keep our service as simple as possible we do not create, use or store profiles of our customers. We only record personally identifiable information and other information that we reasonably require to do business with you. On all NewsMaker pages that collect personally identifiable information, we specifically describe the information that is required in order to provide you with the product or service you request.

### Credit Card Details

NewsMaker and its associated businesses DO NOT keep credit card details. This site uses Paypal and other secure payment gateways to perform secure online credit card transactions and as such all credit card details are entered within the these sites and not on the NewsMaker.com.au site.

NewsMaker and its associated businesses collect personally identifiable information in the following circumstances:

### Membership Database

NewsMaker collects personally identifiable information such as your full name, email address and/or telephone number and other details such as company description whenever you register as a NewsMaker Member. This information is retained as a "boiler plate" to save time the next time you login, in that this type of information repeats itself across press releases. 

### Surveys, promotions and competition information

Occasionally, NewsMaker and/or its associated businesses may offer site visitors or newsletter recipients an opportunity to participate in a survey, promotion or competition. Personally identifiable information collected by NewsMaker or its associated businesses when you participate in a survey, promotion or competition may include your full name, email address, telephone number and street address. 

### Media Commentator Database

NewsMaker and its associated businesses may collect personally identifiable information such as your full name, email address and/or telephone number and other details whenever you submit an application to be included in the Media Commentator Database. 

## Other information we collect:

### Statistical information

When you visit the NewsMaker website we record general information about your visit for statistical purposes. These statistics do not contain any personally identifiable information.

### Cookies

We may, from time to time, use "cookies" to store your preferences, record session information and collect information on how you visit and access our Web pages. We collect information on the Web pages visited by our customers in order to help us to continue improving our services. 

"Cookies" are pieces of information that our Web page transfers to your computer's hard disk for record-keeping purposes. Cookies can make the Web more useful by storing information about your preferences on a particular site. The use of cookies is an industry standard and many Web sites use them to provide useful features for you. Cookies in and of themselves do not personally identify you, only your computer. 

## How We Use Your Information

NewsMaker and its associated businesses use your personally identifiable information only for the purpose of responding to and fulfilling your requests for our products and services. Information collected on NewsMaker may be used to: 

### Purchase NewsMaker products or services

Information collected when we have received confirmation of credit card payment from a merchant facility is used to publish and distribute your press release electronically. Information is retained as a "boiler plate" to save time the next time you login, in that this type of information repeats itself across press releases. We may also contact you about your press release service for the purposes of understanding your satisfaction with the service. 

### Display your details when you next login

NewsMaker displays your details when you next login. This does not include your credit card details as these are not retained by NewsMaker or its associated businesses. 

## Whom We Share Your Information With

NewsMaker and its associated businesses do not disclose any information to anyone except in the following circumstances: 

### Australian Media

NewsMaker provides your press release to the Australian media in accordance with the subject categories or keywords that you have selected. Prior to the press release being distributed you will have the opportunity to deselect specific recipients according to the media company or newspaper / magazine title. 

### Legal obligations

NewsMaker and its associated businesses may be required by law to disclose information provided by you to NewsMaker for the purposes of obtaining products or services from NewsMaker. NewsMaker and its associated businesses may also disclose information against someone who poses a threat to NewsMaker's or and its associated business interests (such as customer fraud) or whose activities could cause harm to others.

## General

If at any time you wish to enquire about any of your personally identifiable information that is stored by NewsMaker please _contact us_.

Email us for any other enquiries or [download the User Guide Presentation](http://www.slideshare.net/newsgal/press-release-services-guide-newsmaker "download the User Guide Presentation.")
